

Carrer de Bruniquer 53 P1 02 Barcelona, Spain M: + 34 696 923 570 manuel.vigo@gmail.com www.manuelvigo.com



Strategic Designer, with an academic background in design methodologies, philosophy and international relations. I have over 7 years of experience in digital marketing, web design strategies, and communication. I'm currently studying a Masters in Design Management, and aim to help organizations find valuable insights and strategies using user-centered design methodologies. I value multidisciplinary and cross-cultural teams and have been fortunate to live and work on 4 continents.

_ Experience

Design and Innovation Intern at IdeaSquare, CERN – 2017 - Present

- Helping to make connections between the CERN scientific community and society (humanitarian organizations, students, computer scientists, designers, and other multidisciplinary teams).
- Hosting and Facilitating Design Thinking and Collaborative Design workshops.
- Matching CERN detector R&D technologies with societal challenges and opportunities.

Marketing & UX Manager, Latin America For Less – 2013 - 2016

- Leading 9-person digital marketing, content, and web development teams.
- Managed web redesign for PeruForLess.com, overseeing design, user experience, SEO, mobile, PPC advertising. Leading to conversion rate improvements of over 59%.
- Managed new brand projects, and led the company's winning proposal for PeruDesignNet, a competition honoring innovative ideas.
- · Hired and managed external SEO and PPC consultants, and executed strategies.

Writer & Researcher, The Rockefeller Foundation & Next City – January — October 2013

- Researched and wrote a weekly article series on Lima's informal economy.
- Partook in the Rockefeller Foundation's Future Scenarios conferences in Lima, helping participants build a framework for understanding the next decades of Lima's growth.
- Wrote a longform feature article examining Lima's Transportation System, for the Forefront series.

News Editor, Peru This Week – July 2011 - June 2013

- News editor for Peru's foremost English-langue news platform. Over 1,800 articles written.
- Edited and researched business, economic, political, and cultural trends, as well as carried out live news reports for BBC Radio 5.
- Managed social-networks with over 29,000 users.

Education



IED Barcelona - Master in Design Management 2017 - PresentFlorida International University - BA. in International Relations and Philosophy 2007 – 2010



Multimedia editing (Ableton Live, Audacity, Logic Pro, Final Cut Pro); Google Analytics Fundamentas Certificate; advanced SEO and AdWords knowledge.



I play guitar, bass, a little bit of piano and drums, and enjoy playing and recording music with friends. I think curiosity is my biggest diver, and love learning new things.